Melvin Alex Mathew Andoor

mandoor1997@gmail.com| +1(774) 365-7755| Linked in | GitHub | Portfolio



Summary

Computer science graduate with 2+ years of experience in software development and web development. Organized deadlineoriented, analytical person and team player with strong learning mindset. Strong knowledge of TDD, BDD, SDLC. Seeking for an opportunity as a Software Development Engineer/ Front-End Engineer.

Education

M.S. Computer Science, University of Massachusetts Dartmouth

Sep 2019- May 2021

B.E. Computer Engineering, University of Mumbai

(GPA - 3.6)(GPA - 3.2)

July 2015-June 2019

Technical Skills

- Languages: Python, Java, SQL, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, Node.is
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, React.js, Django, Flask
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite
- IDE: Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook, Eclipse, PyCharm, MATLAB
- Libraries: scikit-learn, Pandas, Seaborn, NumPy, Matplotlib, Folium, SciPy, D3Js
- Tools: Git, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, Docker, Tableau, Kubernetes, Perforce, AWS
- Others: Heroku, Unity, Android, REST, Linux, Agile, GitHub

Experience

Software Developer | UMass Dartmouth

Sep 2020 – *May* 2021

- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views and user experience resulting in 25% increase in admissions.
- Debugged and reviewed code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.
- Fixed bugs present in the existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved the web functionality and performance.

Full Stack Developer | Bluemount Logistics

Jan 2018 – May 2019

- Developed, tested, and deployed a document generator web app leveraging Django for backend, ReactJS Framework for frontend and PostgreSQL to store and retrieve the data.
- Adopted Agile methodology for development and implemented the design specifications, system flow diagrams, documentation, and testing.
- Used Kubernetes for containerization and Jenkins for continuous integration and deployment. Git was used to maintain the version control. Achieved 80% increase in document generation compared to the existing system.

Frontend Developer Intern | Don Bosco Institute of Technology

July 2017 - Oct 2017

- Developed a visually appealing Front End of the Don Bosco Journal of Science and Engineering and spearheaded a team of UI/UX designers, documenting & creating design documents on confluence for the team to leverage whenever required.
- Designed and developed Home, About and Admin pages using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript. Due to this revenue of the institute was increased by \$200,000 as institute was advertised and many new students were admitted.
- Assessed the UI designs for technical feasibility and constantly updated UI to provide better user experience.

Projects

Job Portal

- Developed a job portal web app using the Django Framework and SQLite Database and used the Indeed API to post the job positions in this web app.
- Wrote and deployed user authorization API's using the Django REST Framework.
- Integrated the XSS input sanitization using DOMPurify to prevent against cross-site scripting attacks and used Git for version control.

Data Visualization: IMDB Movie Ratings and Effect of Covid 19 on Export Import Trade between Countries

CODE

- Analyzed and developed a website which represented the IMDB Movie Ratings dataset from 1916 to 2016 that determined the existing Correlations and Dependencies.
- Found that the correlation between a Movie being the highest grossing and the number of users and critics that voted for the movie was 0.83 strong correlation. With the help of D3js these findings were graphically showcased.
- Analyzed the effects of Covid 19 on Trading between nations and identified that at the initial few periods of the pandemic, trade deficit of all nations was down by almost 700 billion dollars. Designed a World Network Graph leveraging D3.js and ison to present the trade relations between nations.

Certification

KPMG Data Analytics Consulting Certification | Forage **Android Application Development** | MonkFox

August 2020 - No Expiry August 2017 - No Expiry